# **Hyeonmin Lee**



min0921110@gmail.com

I am a postdoctoral researcher at Seoul National University. My research interests lie in network security, especially, DNS and Email security. I have published five papers, three of which were published in top-tier conferences including USENIX Security and The Web Conference (formerly WWW). Also, I have participated in (or led) more than ten research projects with institutions such as Virginia Tech, Rochester Institute of Technology, University of Twente, KAIST, SIDN Labs, NLnet Labs, etc. I have covered a variety of techniques in my research, such as DNS, DNS security (e.g., DNSSEC, DoT, DoH), SMTP, Email security (e.g., STARTTLS), PKI, DANE, TLS, IoT, and edge computing.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher, Network Convergence and Security Lab

Seoul National University

Visiting Researcher, The Center for Cybersecurity

Rochester Institute of Technology

Apr 2022 — Present Seoul, South Korea

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Rochester, NY, United States

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea)

"

o [Dissertation] "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"

o [Advisors] Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Seoul National University) and Prof. Taejoong "Tijay" Chung (Virginia Tech)

**B.S., Computer Science and Engineering**, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea) **Visiting Student, Information Technology**, Uppsala University, (Uppsala, Sweden)

Mar 2011 — Feb 2016

Fall 2014

Mar 2016 — Feb 2022

# **PUBLICATIONS (SELECTED)**

#### [C3] ZTLS: A DNS-based Approach to Zero Round Trip in TLS handshake (To appear)

TheWebConf'23

- o Sangwon Lim, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunsoo Kim, Hyunwoo Lee, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon
- o In Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023, Austin, United States, Apr 2023

#### [C2] Under the Hood of DANE mismanagement in SMTP

**USENIX Security'22** 

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

# [C1] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**USENIX Security'20** 

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung
- o In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2020

#### [I-D] DNSSEC Extension by Using PKIX Certificates

Internet-Draft

- o Hyeonmin Lee, Taekyoung Kwon
- o Active Internet-Draft, Mar 2023

#### RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE (SELECTED)

# Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- o [Keywords] Domain Name System, DNS over TLS (DoT), DNS over HTTPS (DoH), Packet filtering.
- [Roles] **System Designer, Programmer** Investigate a way to filter packets using the information in DNS messages and implement it on BIND9.

# Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

Aug 2022 - Present

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- ∘ [Keywords] Internet of Things (IoT), Machine learning, Abnormal detection.
- [Roles] **Project Manager, System Designer, Programmer** Analyzed IoT network traffic to distinguish abnormal traffic from normal ones using an autoencoder.

## Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity

Apr 2016 — Dec 2020

(Funded by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP))

- o [Keywords] Edge/Cloud computing, Mobility, In-network caching, Trustworthiness.
- [Roles] **Project Manager (Mar 2020 Dec 2020), System Designer, Programmer** Devised/implemented an ID Resolver that handles the mapping between IDs and resources in the edge network (e.g., ID allocation and mobility handling).

#### SKILLS

Tools and Languages Python (proficient), C/C++, Java, Go, Spark, Hadoop, Git, MT<sub>F</sub>X, Linux OS

Quantitative Research DNS, DNS Security (i.e., DNSSEC, DoT, DoH), SMTP, Email Security (i.e., STARTTLS), PKI, DANE, TLS, IoT,

Edge computing

**Communication** English, Korean (native)